Is it love... or are they just imagining things?
Alex & Emma is a comedy, romance film directed by Rob Reiner.
Writer Alex Sheldon must finish his novel within a month.
If he doesn't, he won't get paid.
And, if that happens, angry Mafia types to whom he
owes money will come looking for him.
In order to expedite things, Alex hires typist Emma
Dinsmore and begins dictating his novel.
The book is about a doomed love affair between a character similar
to Alex and a character named Polina Delacroix.
But, as Alex falls for Emma, his work takes a different turn.
Alex Sheldon / Adam Shipley, played by Luke Wilson.
Emma Dinsmore / Ylva / Elsa / Eldora / Anna, played by Kate Hudson.
Polina Delacroix, played by Sophie Marceau.
John Shaw, played by David Paymer.
Bobby / Flamenco Dancer #1, played by Lobo Sebastian.
Tony / Flamenco Dancer #2, played by Chino XL.
Alex & Emma is a 2003 American romantic comedy-drama film directed by
Rob Reiner and starring Kate Hudson and Luke Wilson.
Written by Jeremy Leven, the film is about a writer who must publish a
novel in thirty days or face the wrath of loan sharks.
Alex & Emma was released by Warner Bros.
Pictures on June 20, 2003.
The film received negative reviews from critics and was a box office
bomb, grossing $15 million against a $30 million budget.
The film explores themes of casino, based on novel or book,
gambling, boston, massachusetts, gambling debt.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.